Guide to the Betsy Beinecke Shirley Collection of American Children's Literature
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Authors and Illustrators for Children, 1719-2001; Series I; 8.38; (21 boxes)
  - Hopkins, Livingston
    - Drawings (3) for single-pane comics; ink and pencil on bristol board, undated (Box 9, Folder 200)
  - Howard, Charles J.
    - Drawing, "Hey Diddle Diddle"; pencil on paper, undated
  - Howard, Justin H.
    - Drawing for The Doings of the Alphabet; watercolor and pencil on paper, circa 1869
  - Humphrey, Maud
    - Drawing, "Dolly in Danger," for Little Brighteyes Story Book; watercolor on paper, circa 1901
  - Hurd, Clement
    - Proof print of dust jacket of Goodnight Moon, undated
  - Ives, Sarah Noble
    - Drawings (3) for The Night Before Christmas; watercolor, ink, and pencil on paper, mounted on illustration board, circa 1907
  - Irving, Washington
    - Manuscript leaf from Bracebridge Hall; holograph, 1822 (Box 9, Folder 201)
  - Jefferson, Joseph
    - Correspondence and documents regarding Rip Van Winkle, 1895-1942 (Box 10, Folder 202)
    - Correspondence and documents regarding Intimate Recollections of Joseph Jefferson, by Eugénie Paul Jefferson, 1909 (Box 10, Folder 203)
  - Jenks, Tudor
    - Letters (2) to a boy, regarding an autograph, and to W. W. Denslow acknowledging a misquotation from "Twas the Night Before Christmas", 1895, 1902 (Box 10, Folder 204)
  - Jewett, Sarah Orne
    - Manuscript passage copied from Betty Leicester: A Story for Girls, in Jewett's hand, undated (Box 10, Folder 205)
  - Johnson & Warner
    - Indentures (2), partnership agreement and dissolution of partnership of Philadelphia publishers Jacob Johnson and Benjamin Warner; holograph, 1808, 1816
  - Johnston, David Claypoole
    - Drawing of two women on horseback in front of a cottage; pencil on paper, undated (Box 10, Folder 206)
    - Illustrations from Charcoal Sketches, or Night Scenes in the Metropolis, by J. G. Neal; folio sheet with four etchings, 1838
  - Keely, Mary
    - Manuscript book, "Aunt Mary's Stories"; holograph with illustrations in ink and pencil, 1847 (Box 10, Folder 207)
      Written for William Mason Bailey (1841-1893) and Charles Emerson Bailey (1843-1912) of Waterville, Maine
  - Keller, Arthur Ignatius
    - Drawing, "'I promise to make your little girl happy,' he whispered," for The Virginian, by Owen Wister; gouache on illustration board, framed, 1902
  - Keller, Helen
    - Letters to Michael Anagnostopoulos (2), to her friend Edith (1), and from Edith (1), 1893, undated (Box 10, Folder 208)
    - Manuscript poem, "Autumn"; typescript, undated (Box 10, Folder 209)
  - Kelly, Walt
    - Drawings (11) for "Cinderella and the Three Bears," for Pogo Possum, no. 8; ink and pencil on paper, with a set of hand-colored prints, ink and watercolor on photostat, 1951
  - Kemble, E. W. (Edward Windsor)
    - Letter to Mr. Fraser, regarding baseball, with ink drawing of baseball player, 1891 May 21 (Box 10, Folder 210)
    - Letters (2) to Edward F. Strickland, drawing of a man, and a portrait photograph of Kemble; ink on paper, albumen photograph, 1885 (Box 10, Folder 211)
    - Drawing, "A Corner in Japan," for "The New Orleans Exposition," by Eugene V. Smalley; ink and pencil on bristol board, 1885
      Published in The Century Magazine, May 1885
    - Drawing, "De tall man himself," for "Colonel Carter of Cartersville," by F. Hopkinson Smith; ink on bristol board, 1890 (Box 10, Folder 212)
      Published as "Mister Grocerman," in The Century Magazine, December 1890
    - Tear sheet from Collier's with Kemble cartoon of William Andrews Clark titled "The Nation's Loss," and halftone portrait of Kemble, 1907, undated
  - Kent, Rockwell
    - Print, "Little Red Riding Hood Sets Off for Her Grandmother's," woodcut proof, circa 1920 (Box 10, Folder 213)
  - Kipling, Rudyard
    - Letters (2) to Mary Mapes Dodge, regarding his "Just-So" and "Jungle Book" stories, 1892, circa 1902 (Box 10, Folder 214)
  - Kollner, Augustus
    - Drawing of two female models; ink on paper, undated
  - Lang, Andrew
    - Manuscript, "Red Indian Magic"; holograph, circa 1893 (Box 10, Folder 215)
  - Lathrop, Dorothy Pulis
    - Drawings (8) for Hitty: Her First Hundred Years, by Rachel Field; ink, watercolor, and pencil on paper and illustration board, circa 1929 (Box 10, Folder 216)
    - Drawing for Mr. Bumps and His Monkey, by Walter de la Mare; colored pencil on illustration board, circa 1942 (Box 10, Folder 217)
  - Lawson, Robert
    - Drawing for Ben and Me; ink and Chinese white on paper, circa 1939
    - Print, illustration from The Story of Ferdinand, autographed by Munro Leaf; offset, 1936 (Box 10, Folder 218)
    - Holiday card, sent to Sterling North; signed by "Amos" [of Ben and Me ], 1939 (Box 10, Folder 219)
  - Leaf, Munro
    - Letter to his aunt Sidney, circa 1912 (Box 10, Folder 220)
  - Lear, Edward
    - Letter to James T. Fields, thanking him for sending a book; includes self-portrait of Lear with his cat Foss, 1878 Mar 13 (Box 10, Folder 221)
      Removed from Shirley 4072; envelope remains in book
    - Note to Mary Nicholl [Mrs. Matthew Digby] Wyatt, accepting an invitation; ink on paper; the words form a drawing of a creature, titled below by the artist, "The grate See Sarpint", 1868 Dec 4 (Box 10, Folder 222)
  - Lenski, Lois
    - Letters (2) to Valenti Angelo, regarding Song of St. Francis by Clyde Robert Bulla, 1952, 1953 (Box 10, Folder 223)
    - Drawing for cover of Songs of Mr. Small; ink and watercolor on paper, 1954
  - Leslie, Eliza
    - Letter to unidentified man, regarding Charles Brockden Brown and her own writings, with one clipped signature, 1845, undated (Box 10, Folder 224)
  - Lewis, C. S. (Clive Staples)
    - Letter to Deborah Fraser, regarding his Narnia stories, 1960 Feb 23 (Box 10, Folder 225)
  - Lewis, Dio
    - Manuscript, "Physical Health," for Our Young Folks; holograph, undated (Box 10, Folder 226)
  - Lewis, Earl B.
    - Drawing for Little Cliff's First Day of School, by Clifton L. Taulbert; watercolor and pencil on paper, 2001
  - Lofting, Hugh
    - Drawing of a pelican, inscribed to Jane Ann Bodenheimer; ink on paper, with portrait photograph of Lofting, 1933 Feb, undated (Box 10, Folder 227)
  - Lomax, John Avery
    - "A Half-Million Dollar Song"; typescript, corrected, undated (Box 10, Folder 228)
      Describes how Lomax discovered and made famous the song, "Home on the Range"
  - London, Jack
    - Proof sheet for fragment of text from The Call of the Wild, undated (Box 10, Folder 229)
  - Longfellow, Henry Wadsworth
    See also: Austin, Etta Maria
    - Manuscripts (3) of poems: "The Arrow and the Song," "Voices of the Night," and untitled, 1842-1875 (Box 10, Folder 230)
  - MacDonald, George
    - Letter to "Miss Kingsley," regarding the artist Arthur Hughes, 1885 Dec 1 (Box 10, Folder 231)
  - McLenan, John
    - Drawing, "The Contrast"; ink on paper mounted on illustration board, 1861 (Box 10, Folder 232)
  - McLoughlin Brothers, Inc.
    See also: Richard André, W. Bruton, Harrison Cady, Edward P. Cogger, Anthony Hochstein, Sarah Noble Ives, and Frederick Burr Opper
    - Unidentified artist, drawing for cover of Little Stories for Little Folks; hand-colored proof, circa 1890
    - Unidentified artist, drawing for cover of The Story of the Three Bears; hand-colored proof, circa 1892
    - Unidentified artist, proof prints from pirated editions of Dean's Home Pantomime Toy Books, circa 1880 (Box 10, Folder 233-239)
      Includes stories of Aladdin, Ali Baba, Beauty and the Beast, Blue Beard, Cinderella, Dick Whittington, and Puss in Boots
    - Unidentified artist, proof prints from pirated edition of The Young Ragamuffins, circa 1860 (Box 10, Folder 240)
      Includes marked-up pages from the London edition
  - McVickar, H. W. (Harry Whitney)
    - Documents (2) regarding The Boston Tea Party, by Josephine Pollard, 1882 (Box 11, Folder 241)
    - Drawings (4) for Nellie in Dreamland, by Davison Dalziel; ink, watercolor, and pencil on paper, circa 1884 (Box 11, Folder 242)
  - Melville, Herman
    - Letter to Laura M. Wachslager, regarding sea tales by William Clark Russell, 1885 Jul 12 (Box 11, Folder 243)
  - Merrill, Frank T.
    - Drawing for "Captain January" series, by Laura E. Richards; ink, pencil, and Chinese white on paper, 1893
    - Drawing, "A Merry Christmas"; ink, pencil, and Chinese white on paper mounted on mat board, undated
  - Messinger, Peggy
    - Manuscript containing five verses: "A Man of Pleasure," "A Woman of Pleasure," "On Pleasure," and two "Riddles", 1786 Dec 19 (Box 11, Folder 244)
  - Miller, Bertha E. Mahony
    - Certificate and medal, Constance Lindsay Skinner Achievement Award, presented by the Women's National Book Association, 1955 (Box 11, Folder 245)
    - Medal, Regina Medal, presented by the Catholic Library Association, 1967 (Box 11, Folder 246)
    - Miniature "horn books" made for Bertha and William D. Miller, by Beulah; carved and painted wood, undated (Box 11, Folder 247)
  - Miller, Mary Jane
    - Manuscript booklet, "The History of Little Fanny Exemplified in a Series of Figures"; holograph, [1812?] Feb 19 (Box 11, Folder 248)
  - Mitchell, John Ames
    - Drawing for "My Uncle Jehosaphat"; ink and pencil on illustration board, circa 1876
      Published in St. Nicholas Magazine, January 1876
  - Mitchell, Margaret
    - Letter to Susie Huston, regarding Gone With the Wind, 1937 Feb 8 (Box 11, Folder 249)
  - Moore, Clement Clarke
    - Letters (2) to Rev. James Chapman of Perth Amboy, New Jersey, 1819, 1820 (Box 11, Folder 250)
    - Letters (4) to "Santa Claus" by Thomas and Joseph Chapman, and one from "Santa Claus", 1837-1840 (Box 11, Folder 251)
  - Mora, Jo
    - Drawings (16) for Reynard the Fox; brown ink and wash on paper, 1901
  - Morley, Christopher
    - Manuscript poem, "The Lusitania, Murdered off Kinsdale, Ireland, May 7, 1915"; holograph, undated (Box 11, Folder 252)
  - Morrow, Honoré
    - Autographed index card, undated (Box 11, Folder 253)
      Removed from Shirley 3166
  - Murray, Lindley
    - Letter to Samuel Latham Mitchill, regarding the popularity and copyright of his books for children, 1800 Sep 30 (Box 11, Folder 254)
  - Neill, John R. (John Rea)
    - Drawing, "Tik-Tok of Oz," for Tik-Tok of Oz, by L. Frank Baum; ink and pencil on illustration board, 1914
  - Nesbit, E. (Edith)
    - Contract with Dodd, Mead & Company for Five Children and It, 1905 Nov 24 (Box 11, Folder 255)
  - Newell, Peter
    - Drawing, "Jimmieboy and the Gold Fish," for a John Kendrick Bangs story; ink, wash, and Chinese white on illustration board, 1895
    - Drawings (2), "'Pray, what's the time?' the Turkey said"; ink and pencil on bristol board, 1893 (Box 11, Folder 256)
      Published in Harper's Young People, December 26, 1893
    - Drawing, "The shrapnel bursting o'er his head's the climax of his troubles"; watercolor and pencil on illustration board, undated
    - Drawing, "Signing the Declaration of Indipendence [sic] with Apparent Levity"; ink and watercolor on paper, undated (Box 11, Folder 257)
  - Oakley, Violet
    - Letter to "Margaretta," regarding Oakley's Samuel F. B. Morse, 1940 Jan 17 (Box 11, Folder 258)
  - Opper, Frederick Burr
    - Drawings (8) for "The Jolly Gymnasium"; watercolor, gouache, and pencil on paper, undated
  - Optic, Oliver
    See: Adams, William T. (William Taylor)
  - Parrish, Maxfield
    - Documents regarding A History of New York, by Washington Irving, 1900, 1914 (Box 11, Folder 259)
    - Letter to "Mr. Lane," regarding a visit and calendar, 1910 May 9 (Box 11, Folder 260)
    - Letters (3) between P. F. Collier & Son and Duffield and Company, regarding illustrations for A Wonder Book, and Tanglewood Tales for Girls and Boys, by Nathaniel Hawthorne, 1910 (Box 11, Folder 261)
  - Petersham, Maud Fuller and Miska
    - An American ABC
      - Drawings (8) for initials; pencil on tracing paper, and tempera on paper, circa 1941 (Box 11, Folder 262)
      - Drawings (6) of people and squirrels; pencil on tracing paper, circa 1941 (Box 11, Folder 263)
      - Drawing, "Miki posing for Abe Lincoln"; pencil on paper, circa 1941 (Box 11, Folder 264)
      - Design for cloth cover; tempera on paper, circa 1941 (Box 11, Folder 265)
      - Book dummy; pencil, watercolor, tempera, and collage on paper; bound, circa 1941 (Box 11, Folder 266)
      - Proof sheets (11) for dust jacket, 1941 (Box 11, Folder 267)
      - Proof sheets, complete set, 1941 (Box 11, Folder 268)
      - Proof sheets (13) of letters and vignettes, with sheet of proof text, 1941 (Box 11, Folder 269)
      - Proof sheets (52) of illustrations, 1941 (Box 12, Folder 270)
      - Proof sheets (2) of illustrations not used, 1941 (Box 12, Folder 271)
      - Advertisement/prospectus sheets (3), with Macmillan catalogue cover proof, 1941, undated (Box 12, Folder 272)
      - Proof sheets (10) of pages from third printing, trimmed, folded, unbound, 1942 (Box 12, Folder 273)
    - Book dummy for The Story Book of Trains; ink, pencil, crayon, and opaque watercolor illustrations, with paste-up text printed on glassine, circa 1935 (Box 12, Folder 274)
    - Proof sheets (21) of children and animals; project(s) unidentified, undated (Box 12, Folder 275)
  - Pitz, Henry Clarence
    - Drawings (3) for Robinson Crusoe, by Daniel Defoe; ink on illustration board, circa 1936
  - Pogány, Willy
    - Drawing, "The Emperor holds a stick..." for Gulliver's Travels, by Jonathan Swift; watercolor on paper, framed, circa 1917
  - Porter, Eleanor H. (Eleanor Hodgman)
    - Manuscript pages (24) of Pollyanna Grows Up; holograph, written on verso of correspondence with publishers, dated 1912-1914, undated (Box 12, Folder 276)
  - Potter, Beatrix
    - Letter to Bertha Miller, regarding gifts received, 1942 Jun 18 (Box 12, Folder 277)
  - Pritchard, Edward
    - Dummies (15) of "periodicals"; holograph, illustrated, circa 1888 (Box 12, Folder 278)
      Small "serials" influenced by Horatio Alger's "Fame and Fortune" stories
  - Provenson, Alice and Martin
    - Drawing, cover design for A Peaceable Kingdom: The Shaker Abecedarius; watercolor, ink, and pencil on paper, circa 1981
  - Pyle, Howard
    - Certificate of copyright for Yankee Doodle: An Old Friend in a New Dress, 1881 Oct 13 (Box 12, Folder 279)
    - Drawings (2), headpieces for The Wonder Clock; ink on paper mounted on illustration board, 1885 (Box 12, Folder 280)
      Published in Harper's Young People, December 1885
    - Page proofs (8) of Sabbath Thoughts, undated
  - Rackham, Arthur
    - Letter to Eleanor Farjeon, regarding Rip Van Winkle, 1913 Dec 17 (Box 12, Folder 281)
  - Remington, Frederic
    - Letter to "My dear Bobbie," regarding William Nicholson's An Alphabet, undated (Box 12, Folder 282)
  - Rey, H. A. (Hans Augusto)
    - Drawing for Cecily G and the 9 Monkeys, with presentation letter; ink, pencil, and watercolor on paper mounted on heavy paper, 1954, undated (Box 12, Folder 283)
    - Holiday card and publicity photograph, both signed by author, 1960, 1961 (Box 12, Folder 284)
  - Reynolds, Cuyler
    - Manuscript for The Rosamond Tales; typescript and holograph, circa 1897 (Box 12, Folder 285)
    - Photographs (14 on 13 sheets) for The Rosamond Tales; mounted on pasteboards, annotated with captions and chapter numbers, circa 1897 (Box 12, Folder 286)
    - Photographs (25) for The Rosamond Tales; mounted on pasteboards, annotated with captions and chapter numbers, circa 1897 (Box 13, Folder 287-288)
  - Rhead, Louis
    - Drawings (4 on 1 sheet) for Tom Brown's School Days, by Thomas Hughes; ink and pencil on paper, with printed initial attached for scale, circa 1911
  - Richards, Laura Elizabeth Howe
    - Letters (2) to Mr. Keddie, with typescript and proof of "A Apple Pie", 1938-1939 (Box 13, Folder 289)
  - Richardson, Frederick
    - Drawings (2) for Blue Fairy Book and Red Fairy Book, by Andrew Lang; ink and watercolor on paper, circa 1930
  - Roche, James Jeffrey
    - Tribute to Edward Everett Hale, for The Writer; holograph, undated (Box 13, Folder 290)
  - Rogers, W. A. (William Allen)
    - Drawings (19) for Toby Tyler, or, Ten Weeks with a Circus, by James Otis; ink and pencil on paper mounted on cardboard, circa 1880
      Published in Harper's Young People, December 1880-January 1881
  - Roosevelt, Eleanor
    - Contract for Eleanor Roosevelt's Christmas Book, with Dodd, Mead & Company; signed by the author; accompanied by letter from agent Nannine Joseph to Allen T. Klots Jr., of Dodd, Mead & Co., 1962-1963 (Box 13, Folder 291)
  - Ruskin, John
    - Portrait photograph; albumen print, undated (Box 13, Folder 292)
      Removed from Shirley 2986
  - Russell, William Clark
    - Letter to Mr. Danson, regarding Sampson Lloyd and Russell's books, 1896 Dec 2 (Box 13, Folder 293)
  - Samuel Wood & Sons
    - Copyright certificate for The New York Primer; or Second Book; signed by Secretary of State John Quincy Adams, 1822 Dec 23 (Box 13, Folder 294)
  - Sands, Benjamin
    - Harlequinades (4); ink and watercolor on paper; with patchwork purse made from cuffs of contemporary gloves, lined with silk, circa 1770 (Box 13, Folder 295-296)
    - Harlequinades (4); ink and watercolor on paper, circa 1790 (Box 13, Folder 297)
  - Saunders, Marshall
    - Reader review by Beautiful Joe, and signed photo postcard, 1893, 1933 (Box 13, Folder 298)
  - Sarg, Tony
    - Drawing, "Faust," for The Classics in Slang, by H. C. Witwer; ink, watercolor, and pencil on paper, circa 1926
      Published in Collier's, April 17, 1926
  - Saxe, John Godfrey
    - Letter to James T. Fields, regarding a collection of tales for children, 1863 May 28 (Box 13, Folder 299)
  - Scarry, Richard
    - Drawing of figure in large sombrero riding spotted horse; ink and watercolor on illustration board, undated (Box 13, Folder 300)
  - Schulz, Charles M.
    - Letter to Patricia Moore, regarding Charlie Brown Fan Club, 1957 Oct 22 (Box 13, Folder 301)
  - Sendak, Maurice
    - Drawing of Bilbo Baggins and Gandalf, for "The Hobbit," by J. R. R. Tolkien; ink on paper, 1967 (Box 13, Folder 302)
    - Medal, replica of University of Southern Mississippi de Grummond Medallion; bronze, 1981 (Box 13, Folder 303)
    - Uncorrected proofs of We are All in the Dumps with Jack and Guy, 1993 (Box 13, Folder 304)
  - Seuss, Dr.
    - Stationery items (3) for Dartmouth College Alumni Fund with printed illustrations (correspondence to Mason Dickinson from class agents), 1938, 1940, undated (Box 13, Folder 305)
  - Sewell, Helen
    - Drawings (3) for Ten Saints, by Eleanor Farjeon; ink, pencil, and Chinese white on paper, circa 1936
  - Shepard, Ernest H. (Ernest Howard)
    - Drawing for The Wind in the Willows, by Kenneth Grahame; ink, pencil, and watercolor on paper, framed, circa 1960
  - Sheppard, William Ludwell
    - Proof pages from The Old-Fashioned Mother Goose Melodies, 1879 (Box 14, Folder 306-308)
  - Shimin, Symeon
    - Dust jacket design and artist's dummy for Dance in the Desert, by Madeleine L'Engle; watercolor, ink, pencil on paper, with paste-up text, 1969, undated (Box 14, Folder 309-310)
    - Dummy for Sam, by Ann Herbert Scott; watercolor, ink and pencil on paper, with paste-up text, circa 1966 (Box 14, Folder 311)
  - Shinn, Everett
    - Drawings (7) for The Night Before Christmas, by Clement Clarke Moore; ink, charcoal, watercolor, and pencil on illustration board and on paper, circa 1942
    - Dummy for "The Knights of the Hop-A-Round-Table"; watercolor, ink, and pencil on paper, 1941 (Box 14, Folder 312)
  - Simon
    - Scrimshaw pendant, reproduction of illustration from Alice in Wonderland, engraved "for Betsy Shirley"; ivory, undated (Box 14, Folder 313)
  - Sloane, William
    - Letter to Rosemary Benét, regarding the gift of a book, circa 1940 (Box 15, Folder 314)
      Removed from Shirley +446
  - Smith, E. Boyd (Elmer Boyd)
    - Drawings (7) for "Dumpling's Wonderful Voyage"; ink and pencil on paper, circa 1902 (Box 15, Folder 315)
    - Drawing, "Trouble," for After They Came Out of The Ark; watercolor, ink, and pencil on paper, circa 1918
  - Smith, Jessie Willcox
    - Contracts and correspondence, Duffield & Company, New York, regarding Smith's rights and royalties, including sales of prints on commission, 1908-1925 (Box 15, Folder 316)
    - Painting, "On the top of the great beech-tree," for At the Back of the North Wind, by George MacDonald; oil on artist's board, framed, circa 1919
  - Stallknecht, H. S.
    - Drawing, pictorial anagram puzzle, with ten illustrations forming the enigma "frigates"; ink, pencil, and on paper, circa 1878 (Box 15, Folder 317)
      Published in St. Nicholas Magazine, April 1878
  - Stephens, H. L. (Henry Louis)
    - Drawing for "An Alphabet from England" by Christina G. Rossetti; ink on bristol board, 1875 (Box 15, Folder 318)
      Published in St. Nicholas Magazine, November 1875
    - Letters (5) to Benson J. Lossing, regarding commissioned drawings of De Soto, Washington, the death of Wolfe, and other subjects, 1867-1868 (Box 15, Folder 319)
    - Proof sheets of illustrations for various publications, 1860s (Box 15, Folder 320)
  - Stowe, Harriet Beecher
    - Letters to I. C. Webster and O. H. Peck, regarding her sources for characters in Uncle Tom's Cabin, and conditions in Florida, 1886, undated (Box 15, Folder 321)
  - Stratemeyer Syndicate
    Contains drawings acquired as a group; created for Syndicate publications or used in reprints published by the Syndicate. Material related to Edward Stratemeyer is filed in Series III.
    - Angell, Clare
      - Drawing for Lost at Sea, by Horatio Alger, Jr.; ink and gouache on illustration board, circa 1904
    - Bridge, W. B.
      - Drawing for When Santiago Fell, by Ralph Bonehill; ink and gouache on illustration board, circa 1914
    - Nuttall, Charles
      - Drawing, "The circus," for The Bobbsey Twins in the Country, by Laura Lee Hope; gouache on illustration board, circa 1903
    - Rogers, Walter S.
      - Drawings (2) for The Rover Boys Down East, by Arthur M. Winfield; ink and gouache on illustration board, circa 1911
    - Shute, A. B.
      - Drawing, "'You shall go on board,' said Dan Baxter," for The Rover Boys on the River, by Arthur M. Winfield; gouache and pencil on illustration board, circa 1905
      - Drawings (2) for The Young Book Agent, by Horatio Alger, Jr.; gouache on illustration board, circa 1905
      - Drawings (2) for The Young Volcano Explorers, by Edward Stratemeyer; gouache on illustration board, circa 1902
    - Unidentified artist
      - Drawings (3) for With Boone on the Frontier, by Ralph Bonehill; ink and gouache on illustration board, circa 1903
  - Sully, Thomas
    - Letter to Daniel Appleton, regarding drawings of F. O. C. Darley, 1842 Aug 31 (Box 15, Folder 322)
  - Tarkington, Susanah
    - Letter of thanks to Miss Little on behalf of Booth Tarkington, undated (Box 15, Folder 323)
  - Taylor, Bayard
    - Letter to William Ticknor, regarding a series of stories for "young folks", 1866 Apr 6 (Box 15, Folder 324)
  - Tenggren, Gustaf
    - Drawing, "My Old Kentucky Home," for Sing for America, by Opal Wheeler; watercolor and pencil on illustration board, circa 1944
    - Letter to Mrs. Arthur Vorwald, regarding his life and work, 1938 Jun 21 (Box 15, Folder 325)
  - Tenniel, John, Sir
    - Letters (2) to Miss Chappell, regarding his work, 1886-1887 (Box 15, Folder 326)
  - Terhune, Albert Payson
    - Letter to Mrs. Kibbe, regarding Lad: A Dog, 1919 May 7 (Box 15, Folder 327)
  - Thackeray, William Makepeace
    - Letter to unidentified boy, regarding his request for an autograph; with photograph of Thackeray and reprint of letter issued as holiday greeting by collector Thomas F. Madigan, 1852-1928
  - Thoreau, Henry David
    - Poem, "Fair Haven"; holograph, 1843 May 2 (Box 15, Folder 328)